<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://ali-maq.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://ali-maq.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2026-01-16T06:08:01+00:00</updated><id>https://ali-maq.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Ali Quidwai</title><subtitle>AI Systems Engineer at Mount Sinai | Precision Oncology | Multi-Agent Systems | Clinical AI | 70+ Citations </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Why I’m Finally Building in Public</title><link href="https://ali-maq.github.io/blog/2026/welcome/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why I’m Finally Building in Public"/><published>2026-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2026-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ali-maq.github.io/blog/2026/welcome</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ali-maq.github.io/blog/2026/welcome/"><![CDATA[<p>For years, I’ve built tools that stayed locked in production silos. Internal pipelines. Clinical systems. Things that worked, but that nobody outside my team would ever see.</p> <p>That changes this year.</p> <h2 id="the-problem-with-building-in-private">The Problem with Building in Private</h2> <p>When you work in clinical AI, there’s a natural tendency toward secrecy. Patient data is sensitive. Institutional knowledge feels proprietary. And honestly, it’s easier to ship fast when you’re not thinking about documentation.</p> <p>But I’ve started to feel the cost of this approach. Every time I solve a problem, I solve it alone. Every time someone else hits the same wall, they start from scratch. The wheel gets reinvented constantly.</p> <h2 id="what-im-sharing">What I’m Sharing</h2> <p>This site is my commitment to building in public. Here’s what you’ll find:</p> <p><strong>Projects</strong> — Production systems I’ve built at Mount Sinai, including multi-agent architectures, GPU-accelerated pipelines, and clinical RAG systems. Where possible, I’ll share code, architectures, and lessons learned.</p> <p><strong>Publications</strong> — My papers on genomic curation, clinical decision support, and AI-generated text detection. All with links to preprints and code.</p> <p><strong>Blog</strong> — Deep dives into problems I’m solving. Not polished tutorials—more like field notes from someone figuring things out in real time.</p> <h2 id="what-im-learning">What I’m Learning</h2> <p>I’m also using this year to go deeper on <strong>model interpretability</strong>. I’ve spent years making models work. Now I want to understand <em>why</em> they work—and more importantly, when they don’t.</p> <p>I’m currently participating in SPAR and other AI safety programs. Expect posts on mechanistic interpretability, feature visualization, and what happens when you actually look inside the black box.</p> <h2 id="lets-connect">Let’s Connect</h2> <p>If you’re working on multi-agent systems, clinical AI, or interpretability—I’d love to hear from you. The best ideas come from unexpected conversations.</p> <p>You can reach me at <a href="mailto:quidwaiali@gmail.com">quidwaiali@gmail.com</a> or connect on <a href="https://linkedin.com/in/mujahid-ali-q">LinkedIn</a>.</p> <p>Let’s build something.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="personal"/><category term="open-source"/><category term="reflections"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[After years of keeping tools locked in production, I'm committing to open source.]]></summary></entry></feed>